[Teach me! Ginpachi Sensei]
Teach me! Ginpachi Sensei
(銀時)
ﾍﾟﾝﾈｰﾑ 銀世界さんからの質問｡
Pen name Gin World asks:
真選組は
いったい何人いるんですか？
How many members are there
in the Shinsengumi?
In Episode 20, about the
mosquito-like Amanto,
第20話の
蚊みたいな 天人の話では➡
18人が隊士の
半分以上となっていましたけど➡
they said 18 members
were "more than half."
Since the Shinsengumi
has up to Squad 10
真選組は 十番隊まであるから➡
that means there are only
2-3 people per squad.
それだと１つの隊に２～３人しか
いないことになっちゃいます｡
Is the Shinsengumi comprised
of 35-36 men?
真選組は本当に
35～36人の人数なんですか？
Okay, here's your answer.
はい ｽﾞﾊﾞﾘお答えします！
真選組は 定期的に隊士を募って➡
The Shinsengumi regularly recruits members
and has grown into a giant organization.
日々
巨大な組織になっているんです｡
動乱編で 近藤が
故郷に行こうとしてるのも➡
In the Crisis Arc, Kondo tried
to return to his hometown
because he wanted to recruit members.
新隊士を募るためです｡
Currently, there are roughly
10 men per squad.
現在は １つの隊10人前後です｡
あとちなみに 過去の
話数を一時停止したりして➡
By the way, you must never go back
and pause previous episodes
人数を数えたりは
決してしないように！
to count the number of people.
In anime, 10 or more are
counted as "many."
ｱﾆﾒでは
10人以上はたくさんて数えます｡
というわけで 転入生の斉藤
とりあえず廊下に立ってなさい！
And so, transfer-student Saito, go
and stand outside in the hallway!
[Note: Saito is the new editor for GinTama manga.]
[Earlier, when we received a large amount of mail supporting us, a bigwig said, "Something's going on, right?"]
[Three years and still zero trust. Anime
"GinTama" continues its popular run!!]
((組員:わかるか 京次郎｡
Do you understand, Kyojiro?
This is you...
ｺｲﾂがお前だ｡
狛犬ってのはなぁ
常に主の前に立ち➡
The Guardian dog always stands
in front of his master,
その場を動かずいろんなもんから
主を守り続けてるんだ｡
unmoving, protecting his
master from all harm.
見ろよ この面構え｡
立派じゃねえかよ｡
Look at this face...isn't it magnificent?
お前もこの狛犬のように➡
I think you can grow up
into a man as noble,
気高く 雄大な強い男に
なれるんじゃろうかのう？
majestic and strong as
this Guardian dog.
まぁ それも
お前次第じゃ がんばれよ))
But that really depends
on you. Work hard...
♪♪～
(新八)あっ！
うお～っ でけえ～っ！
Whoa! It's huge!
You know, I think it's finally happening!
ちょっと これは
今回きたんじゃないですか？
何の仕事か知らないけど➡
I don't know what sort of job this is,
but I think we can look forward to
major compensation this time!
今回は報酬
期待できるんじゃないですか！
(神楽)ｳﾎﾎｯｰ！
今夜はごちそういっぱいｱﾙな！
We'll be feasting tonight!
こんな送り迎えなんて
初めてっすもんね！
After all, we've never been
picked up like this!
Quiet, you two. You're embarrassing us.
うるせえよ ｵﾒｴらは｡
恥ずかしいだろ｡
あぁ すみませんねぇ｡
Thank you.
幕府の高官かなんかですかね？
Think it's a top Bakufu official?
ｵﾚたちも有名になったもんだな｡
(神楽)はりきっていこう！
We've become quite famous.
Let's do our best.
♪♪～
あぁ～っ！
["Kids Don't Understand How Their Parents Feel"]
銀さん 体中に穴が開きそうです｡
Gin-san...I feel like I could be shot
full of holes at any moment.
This goes way beyond
giving us the evil eye.
ﾒﾝﾁって ﾚﾍﾞﾙじゃねえぞ｡
ﾔﾂら 目から
ﾋﾞｰﾑ出そうとしてんじゃねえか？
Think they're trying to fire laser
beams at us with their eyes?
いいか 恐らくこれから➡
Listen, they're probably going to tell us
to deliver some white powder for them.
ｵﾚたちはまっ白い粉を運べとか➡
そういうことを
言われるかもしれんが➡
きっとそれは 小麦粉だから
黙って おとな～しく運ぶんだぞ｡
I'm sure it's flour, so just quietly
do as they say, okay?
わかったｱﾙ｡
やめてください 銀さん｡
Understood.
Stop that Gin-san. Don't
give up hope so soon.
早々に諦めないでください｡
(下愚蔵)ｱﾝﾀら万事屋か？
You guys the Odd jobs?
よく来てくれた｡
Thanks for coming.
I'm your client, Kaguzo Mashiroi,
boss of the Mashiroi Gang.
[Note: In Japanese: Mashiroi Kaguzo can mean
"I'm gonna sniff some white (powder)."]
わしが依頼者の魔死呂威組
組長 魔死呂威 下愚蔵じゃ｡
Uh-oh, he's about to sniff
some white powder.
やべぇよ…
まっ白い粉 かぐ気 満々だよ｡
今回 ｱﾝﾀら 呼んだのは
他でもない｡
The reason I called you here
today is...look over there...
ほれ あそこに
倉が見えるじゃろ？
See that storehouse?
実は あそこに まっしろ…｡
Inside, is the...
やべぇよ｡ きたよ おい…｡
まっ白い粉 ﾏｼﾞ きたよ！
Uh-oh, here he comes...
the white powder.
the Mashiroi...
[Note: In Japanese: Mashiroi is a
homonym that can mean "white."]
魔死呂威組の跡取り わしの
１人息子 魔死呂威 鬱蔵が➡
The Mashiroi Gang's successor...my
only son, Utsuzo Mashiroi,
[Note: In Japanese: Utsuzo means "depressed and stored away" and "to shoot up." So Utsuzo Mashiroi can mean "I'm gonna shoot up some white (powder)."]
who's locked himself in there.
引きこもって
出てこんのじゃ～い！ うぉ～!!
えっ？
Huh?
(下愚蔵)鬱蔵が ここから➡
Five years ago Utsuzo locked himself
in there and never came out.
出てこんようになったのは
５年前じゃ｡
He detested becoming a yakuza
and went to earn an honest living
ﾔｸｻﾞになることを嫌い ｶﾀｷﾞとして➡
as an apprentice at a textile wholesaler.
呉服問屋に
奉公に出ていたというのに➡
突然 奉公先から逃げ帰ってきて
倉に 日用品を運び込み➡
But then he abruptly returned
from his apprenticeship,
moved all his personal effects into the storehouse
and hasn't stepped foot outside since.
以来 一歩も 外に
出てこんようになってしもうた｡
わしも この５年
顔を合わせたことがない｡
I haven't even seen him
the past five years.
おい おい… そりゃ もう
中で おっ死んでんじゃねえの？
C'mon, are you sure he's not
already dead in there?
銀さん やめて！
Stop it, Gin-san.
No, I haven't seen or spoken
to him for five years,
(下愚蔵)いや この５年
会ったことも➡
話したこともないが 食事や
欲しいものを書いた紙切れが➡
but a note with his meal requests and things he wants
appears between the gap in the door every day.
毎日 扉の隙間から出てくる｡
(神楽)あっ！ ﾎﾝﾄね｡ 出てきたｱﾙ｡
You're right. There's one now.
Boss!
(組員)おじき！
お～い！ 『ｱﾆﾒｰｼﾞｭ』と ｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣
それに ﾍﾌﾟｼNEXじゃ！
Guys! Animage, JUMP
and a Hepsi NEX!
[Note: Parody of Pepsi NEX. Animage is an
anime magazine from Tokuma Shoten.]
(組員たち)へい！ うぉ～!!
Got it!
(下愚蔵)ﾔｸｻﾞの息子が
引きこもり…｡
A yakuza's son shutting himself off...
そんなことが 外に知れれば
ﾒﾝﾂが命のﾔｸｻﾞは やってけねえ｡
If word got out-my reputation is everything-I
could never remain a yakuza.
I've been so concerned about how it would
look even though I know it's silly,
そんなくだらん体裁ばかり
気にして わしは息子と➡
that I haven't even confronted
my son face-to-face.
正面から向き合わず 気づけば
５年の月日が経っていた｡
By the time I realized it,
five years had passed.
鬱蔵を ここまで追い込んだのは
わしの責任だ｡
I'm responsible for driving
Utsuzo into going this far.
I'm willing to do anything
to get my son back.
息子の人生を
取り戻すためならば➡
わしは
なんだって やるつもりでいる｡
だが… 情けない話だが 何を
やっていいのか わからんのだ｡
...But as pitiful as this sounds,
I don't know what I should do.
人の親とは こんなとき
何をやればいいのだ？
What should a parent do
in a situation like this?
そこで 黙って見てればいいさ｡
Just stand there and watch.
その気持がありゃ 十分だ｡
あとは ｵﾚたちに任せな｡
If you feel that way, that's enough.
Leave the rest to us.
ﾔｸｻﾞにﾃﾞﾘｹｰﾄな仕事は向かねえだろ｡
Yakuza aren't comfortable
with delicate work, right?
ｱﾝﾀら…｡
...You people...
要は 息子を 倉から
引きずりだせばいいんだな？
Essentially, you want us to drag your
son out of the storehouse, right?
おい 神楽｡
うん｡
Hey, Kagura.
出てこい ｺﾗ!! 働け ﾊﾞｶ息子！
Come on out! Get a job, you stupid son!
おい！
それ ﾔｸｻﾞでもできるだろうが!!
Hey! Even yakuza could've done that!
ﾃﾞﾘｹｰﾄの意味 知ってる!?
Do you know what "delicate" means?
Young Boss!
(組員)若！
(組員)おんどりゃ～！
Dammit! What the hell are you doing?!
何 さらしとんじゃ!!
なっ！ ま… 待ってください！
Just a minute. We understand,
we understand.
わかってます わかってますよ！
ﾃﾞﾘｹｰﾄにやりますから!!
We'll be more delicate! Just don't kill us!
命だけは勘弁してください！
なんだよ？ この状況…｡ 命がけで
ﾈﾀ披露する お笑い芸人？
What is all this?
Are these guys comedians doing
a life-or-death routine?!
I feel like a fawn that's stumbled
into the polar bear cage.
白ｸﾏの檻に迷い込んだ
子鹿ともいうｱﾙ｡
ﾎﾞｸらの命が
風前の灯火であることには➡
What hasn't changed is our lives
are still hanging by a thread here.
なんら 変わりはありませんよ｡
Please be delicate.
ﾈﾀも言動も
ﾃﾞﾘｹｰﾄにお願いしますよ！
あなたは 完全に包囲されている｡
We have you completely surrounded.
おとなしく 抵抗をやめ
出てきてください！
Cease your resistance and
come out peacefully!
あ～ もし こちらの要求を
受け入れない場合 朝夕 問わず➡
If you don't do as we say,
we will repeat our demands every
two hours, morning and night!
２時間おきに この説得を
繰り返し 続けることになる！
目の下に ｸﾏがこべりつく前に
あきらめて 出てきたほうが➡
Do yourself a favor by giving yourself
up before you get raccoon eyes!
身のためだぞ！
ｸﾏの檻に放り込むぞ ｺﾗ！
Otherwise we'll throw you
into a bear cage, dammit!
That's not very convincing!
だから それ
説得になってないから！
(組員)なめてんじゃねえぞ ｺﾗ！
Don't play games, dammit!
Don't think you can get away with
threatening a yakuza's son!
(組員)ﾔｸｻﾞの息子 ゆすって
ただで済むと思うな ｺﾗ！
うわ～っ！
Huh? It's a note! A note just came out!
あっ！ あれ 紙切れが…
紙切れが出てきた!!
きっと 心境に
何か 変化があったんですよ！
He must've had a change of heart!
おじき！
Boss!
(下愚蔵)２ｷﾛﾊﾞﾄﾙ？
Two-kilobattle...?
[Note: Refers to NHK's "On Air Battle." Amateur comedians perform for 100 judges who drop golf balls in a bucket if they like the comedian. Kilobattle (KB) is the unit used to measure the weight of the bucket. 545 KB is a perfect score and 93KB is a zero score.]
《低すぎねえ？》
Isn't that score a bit low?
(下愚蔵)なんじゃ!? こりゃ！
What the hell is this?!
見て わからないの？
七輪だよ 七輪｡
Can't you tell? It's a charcoal brazier.
I could tell that by looking.
What I was asking was...
んなもの 見りゃわかる｡
わしが言いたいのは…｡
No, no. Say no more. This
is my strategy. I call it...
ﾉﾝﾉﾝ！ 皆まで言うな｡
これは れっきとした戦略だ｡
題して…｡
題して？
You call it...
あれ？ ちょっと
なんか 楽しくない？ って➡
Huh? That looks like fun.
扉を少し開けて のぞいてみたら
引きずり出されちゃったよ大作戦｡
When he opens the door a crack
to peek out, we drag him out!
That's the plan!
説明しよう！ あれ？ ちょっと
なんか 楽しくない？ って➡
Let me explain.
The "Huh? That looks like fun.
When he opens the door
a crack to peek out,
扉を少し開けて のぞいてみたら➡
we drag him out!" plan works like this...
引きずり出されちゃったよ
大作戦とは➡
First, we grill meat or something
on this charcoal brazier.
まず ﾎﾞｸたちが この七輪を使って
肉かなんかを焼き始めます｡
わいわいがやがやと 楽しい宴会を
行い 若さんの興味をひき…｡
Then we throw a lively party to attract
the Young Boss's attention.
…って それ 天岩戸
そのままじゃねえか!!
You're just retelling the
story of Amanoiwato!
[Note: Parody of the Amaterasu myth. She shut herself
in a cave and the gods threw a party to lure her out.]
ちなみに 私が 扉を無理やり
こじ開ける役ね｡
Just to let you know, forcing
the doors open is my job!
知るか!!
お前ら いい加減にしろ！
Who cares?! Enough of this silliness!
まったく これだから極道もんは
せっかちでいけねえや｡
Man, you yakuza have no patience.
うん？
ｵﾚたち 万事屋が➡
Did you really think we Odd Jobs would come
up with such a simple-minded plan?
そんな安易な作戦を
立てると思ってんのかい？
いや さっきから
安易な作戦ばっかりだと思うが｡
All of your plans up to now
have been simple-minded.
この作戦には まだ続きがある｡
There's more to this plan. In other
words, it has two stages!
つまり 二段構えと
言うべきであろう｡
二段構えだと!?
Two stages, you say?!
Let me explain!
説明しよう！ もし 宴会に
興味を示さなかった場合➡
If he doesn't show interest in our party,
七輪の上の具材は そのまま ｶﾞｷを
いぶし出すための嫌がらせになる｡
we'll leave the food on the brazier
and use it to smoke the kid out!
やめれ～っ!!
Stop it!
(組員)やっぱ ﾅﾒてんぞ ｺｲﾂら！
You're playing games with us!
Don't think you can make fools
of yakuza and get away with it!
(組員)極道 こけにして
ただですむと思っとんのか ｺﾞﾗｧ!!
すみません！ すみません!!
もう しませんから！
We're sorry. We won't do it
anymore! Really, we won't!
ﾎﾝﾄ もうしませんから～!!
おっ また紙が出てきたぞ｡
Oh, it's another note.
おじき！
Boss!
(下愚蔵)ｹﾑい｡
Smoky...
(みんな)確かに…｡
Definitely.
あぁ もう わかった わかった｡
こうなったら最後の手段だ｡
Oh, okay, okay! We'll use our last resort.
何じゃい！ 何か 策があるのか？
What is it? Do you have a plan?
ある！ もう確実に出てくる方法が
たったひとつ ある！
I do! There's one way to
definitely get him out!
おい 神楽｡
あれｱﾙな？
Hey, Kagura!
That plan, huh?
出てこい ｺﾗｱｧ！ 働け ﾊﾞｶ息子！
Come on out! Get a job, you stupid son!
それ 最初だから！
That was the first thing you
tried! The first, not the last!
最後じゃなくて
最初の手段だから!!
(組員)若！
(組員)何さらしとんじゃ！
Young Boss!
Dammit! What the hell are you doing?!
あっ また出た｡
若さん 無事ですよ｡
Another note! He's still all right!
(下愚蔵)ﾎﾝﾄじゃ｡
Really?!
(下愚蔵)うん？
[Farewell.]
This is his dying message!
(下愚蔵)
これ ﾀﾞｲｲﾝｸﾞﾒｯｾｰｼﾞじゃろうが！
(組員)何さらしてｹﾂかんねん！
このﾎﾞｹがぁ！
What the hell have you
done?! You idiots!
(組員)
どう落とし前つけるつもりじゃ！
What're you going to do about this?!
え～っ!?
(中村)おい そのへんにしとけ｡
Hey, that's enough.
(中村)こりゃ 血じゃないわい｡
ﾄﾏﾄｼﾞｭｰｽじゃのう。
This isn't blood. It's tomato juice.
若は ちゃんと
野菜もとっとるらしいわ｡
Seems the Young Boss
is eating his vegetables.
わしゃ 安心した｡
I'm relieved.
Brother!
(組員たち)ｱﾆｷ！
誰だ あれ｡
ｳﾁの若頭 中村 京次郎じゃ｡
Who's that?
That's our junior boss,
Kyojiro Nakamura.
(下愚蔵)鬱蔵が まだ外にいる頃
兄のように慕っていたﾔﾂよ｡
Utsuzo thought of him like a brother back
when he was still out and about.
(下愚蔵)鬱蔵のことは
このわしより詳しい｡
He knows Utsuzo better than I do.
(中村)おじき
いい大人が揃いも揃って➡
Boss, it's appalling to see all these
adults made fools of by a kid.
子供にからかわれてりゃ
世話ないのう｡
わしは… 息子と
正面から向き合うと決めた｡
I've...decided to deal with
my son face-to-face.
もう遅いさ｡ 鬱蔵のことは
ほうっておいたほうがいい｡
It's too late for that.
You should just leave Utsuzo alone.
時がくれば
自分から出てくるじゃろう｡
When the time is right, he'll
come out on his own.
(中村)これ以上
鬱蔵を傷つけるな｡
Don't hurt Utsuzo any more
than you already have.
ｱﾝﾀが ｱｲﾂに何をしたか
忘れたとは言わせんけんのう｡
I won't let you forget what you did to him.
うっ…｡
ｺﾞﾎｯ ｺﾞﾎｯ ｺﾞﾎｯ…｡
(組員たち)おじき！
B-Boss!
Boss, hold on!
おじき！ しっかりしろ｡
ｺﾞﾎｯ…｡
半蔵！ すぐ 駕籠を用意しろ｡
(半蔵)へ… へい！
Hanzo! Get a gurney, now!
R-Right!
おい しっかりしろ｡
おじき！ おじき！
銀さん！
Hey! Pull yourself together, Boss!
Boss!
Gin-san!
お前たちは 病院についてけ｡
銀ちゃんは どうするｱﾙか？
The two of you go with
them to the hospital.
What about you, Gin-chan?
ｵﾚか？ ｵﾚは…｡
Me? I...
(中村)そうか… いや 今夜は
みんな ついててやってくれや｡
I see... No, you men
stay with him tonight.
(中村)あぁ こっちは
わしがおるけん 心配いらんわ｡
Yeah...I'll take care of things
here. Don't worry about it.
若にも わしが ﾒｼ出しとく｡
I'll bring Young Boss his meal.
ｶﾞｷが邪魔だ？
おじきが呼んだ連中か｡
Huh? The kids are a nuisance?
You mean the kids the boss
hired? Ignore them.
ほうっておけ｡
ひでぇ話じゃねえか｡
How cruel is that?
親父が倒れたのに
びくともしやがらねえ｡
His father collapsed, but
he won't even budge.
(中村)依頼者が倒れたんじゃ｡
Your client collapsed.
こんなところにおっても
ﾑﾀﾞじゃろう｡
There's no reason for you
to remain here, is there?
面が見てぇだけだ｡
I just want to see his face-
親父の死に際にも動かねえ
頑固息子の面を｡
the face of the obstinate son who won't
budge even as his father is about to die.
気ぃついとったんかい｡
...You suspected, didn't you?
(中村)そんだけのこと
したんじゃ｡ おじきは｡
...What the Boss did was that bad...
ほら｡
Here.
Hey, is this okay? Isn't
this for the idiot son?
おい いいのかよ｡
これ ﾊﾞｶ息子のじゃねえのか？
ええんじゃ｡
Never mind. Only those who work
can enjoy the taste of sake.
酒の味は 働いとるもんにしか
わからんけぇのう｡
わしは 若のことは
まだ ちっこいｶﾞｷの頃から➡
I've known the Young Boss
since he was a little kid.
知っちょるがの｡
気が弱くて 優しくて➡
He was meek, gentle, and despised the
yakuza way of life even back then.
昔から
この極道の世界を嫌っとった｡
また この世界で生きていける
器でもなかったしのう｡
He didn't have what it takes
to live in this world.
おじきの反対 押し切って
ｶﾀｷﾞの道を選んだんじゃ｡
He chose to make an honest living
against the Boss's wishes.
(中村)そりゃ 楽しそうに
働いとったが➡
He seemed happy at his job...
But that didn't last long.
それも 長くは続かんかった｡
It was the Boss.
(中村)おじきじゃ｡
Utsuzo was his heir.
おじきは 跡取りたる鬱蔵を
極道の世界に連れ戻そうと➡
Boss tried to bring him back to the
yakuza world by showing up
at the Young Boss's workplace and
harassing the store over and over.
若の奉公先にまで ﾂﾗ 出して
店に 数々の嫌がらせをしこんだ｡
身内じゃ いうのも ﾊﾞﾗされて
あっというまに ｸﾋﾞじゃ｡
Once people found out they were related,
Utsuzo was immediately fired.
(中村)若が
こんなことになっとるんは➡
It's all the Boss's fault that the
Young Boss is the way he is.
全部 おじきのせいなんじゃ｡
He's making a big fuss now
over getting the Young Boss
さんざん 若 ほったらかしといて
今さら あわてふためいて➡
out after ignoring him all this time because
he knows his death is imminent.
外に出そうとしとるのも ﾃﾒｴの
死期がわかって おっ死ぬ前に➡
He's desperately trying to make his
son succeed him before he dies.
跡を継がせようと
必死なんだろうよ｡
虫のいい話と思わんか？
Don't you think that's self-serving?
ごちゃごちゃ 理屈は
よく わからねえよ｡ けどよ…｡
I don't know all the messy details, but...
Does a parent who wants to see his
child before he dies need a reason?
死ぬ前に 親が子に
会いたいっていうのによ➡
いちいち 理由があんのかよ｡
子が 親に会うのに
理由が必要なのかよ｡
Does a child need a reason
to see his parent?
Utsuzo...is Utsuzo here...?
鬱蔵… 鬱蔵はいないのか？
親子が会う理由なんざ
ﾂﾗが見たい… それだけで➡
Do a father and son need a reason?
They want to see each other's faces-isn't
that reason enough?
十分じゃねえのかよ？
お前… いい男じゃのう｡
You're...a good man.
ﾍｯ！ 男に言われたって
嬉しくねえよ｡
Hearing that from a guy doesn't
make me happy at all.
悪いが 心の殻 かぶってようが
なんだろうが➡
Sorry. Regardless of whether
he has his heart in a shell,
殻ごと引きずって
連れていかせてもらうぜ｡
I'm dragging him shell
and all to his father.
出てきやがれ！
Come on out. We're going to punch
your dying father in the face.
死にかけた親父のﾂﾗ
１発 ぶん殴りにいくぞ｡
開いた？
It opened?
(中村)まったく…
その扉を開けさせるたぁ➡
Man, I give you credit for making
him open that door.
たいした野郎じゃ｡
♪♪～
あら… 交代の時間？
ちょっと早くない？
Is it time to change shifts?
Isn't it a little early?
A woman?
女!?
Who are you? Where's Utsuzo?
お前 誰だ!? 鬱蔵は？
(中村)いねえよ｡ そんなﾔﾂぁ
とっくに この世にはいねえ｡
He's not here.
He left this world a long time ago.
お前… 誰だ？
Who...are you?
鬱蔵は…｡
いねえよ｡
Where's Utsuzo?
He's not here.
そんなﾔﾂは とっくに
この世には いねえ！
He left this world a long time ago.
♪♪～
ぐはっ！
くっ！
♪♪～
まったく… 腕っぷしまで
一流ときやがったか…｡
Man, your skills are top-notch... Looks
like I got caught by the wrong guy.
とんでもねえのに
目えつけられちまったな…｡
Damn you. What's going on here?!
ﾃﾒｪ どういうこった これは!?
だから 言うたじゃろ｡
今さら ﾊﾞｶ息子➡
I already told you. It's too late to
drag out the stupid son now.
引きずり出そうちゅうても
遅いて｡
どいつも ｺｲﾂも
めでたいﾔﾂらじゃ｡
Those guys are all idiots.
５年も姿も見ず 声も聞かんで
どうして生きてると？
They haven't seen the guy or heard
his voice for five years-
how's he supposed to be still alive?
おじきが悪いんじゃ｡
せっかく ｶﾀｷﾞになって➡
It's the Boss's fault.
Just when I thought his son went straight
and wasn't in my way anymore,
邪魔者が いなくなったと
思っとったら➡
わざわざ連れて帰ってきよって｡
he goes and drags him back.
あの人にいられると
わしは 一生出る幕がないんじゃ｡
If the son's around I'll
never get my chance.
仕方ないんで 一生 殻から➡
There was nothing I could do about it,
so I made sure he would never
come out of his shell.
出てこられんように
させてもらったわ｡
どんなに呼びかけようと
叫ぼうとも➡
No matter how much anyone called
out to him or yelled at him,
もう
若が 外に出てくることはない｡
the Young Boss was never
going to come out.
なんせ殻の中は
骨しかないからのう｡
I mean, all that's left inside
his shell are bones.
この先 ずっと 若は 殻の中じゃ｡
The Young Boss will forever
remain in his shell in here,
おじきが死んでも ずっと｡
even if the Boss dies.
おじきには 気の毒じゃが➡
Too bad for the Boss, but he'll see
his precious son in the other world.
愛しい息子とは あの世で
会ってもらうことになるのう｡
…ﾃﾒｴか？
あ？
Was it you?
鬱蔵をやったのは
ﾃﾒｴかって聞いてんだよ｡
I'm asking you if you're the
one who killed Utsuzo.
…ﾌｯ｡ ﾊﾊﾊ!!
(中村)わしは 昔
若の世話役をやっとった｡
Back then I looked after the Young Boss.
引きこもった後も わしだけは
若も 会ってくれてのう｡
Even after he shut himself away, the
Young Boss would see only me.
It was a cinch to set things up.
細工をするなんざ お手のものよ｡
It'd have been trouble if there was a fuss.
騒ぎになっては
面倒じゃけんのう｡
組長が死んでも
倉から出てこん ﾊﾞｶ息子｡
The foolish son won't come
out even though Boss dies.
代わりに 組を仕切るもんが
必要じゃろ｡
The gang will need someone
to take his place, right?
そうじゃ 頼りにならん
跡取りなんぞじゃない｡
That's right. You can't have the
unreliable heir take over.
腕も 頭もきれる｡
You need someone with sharp
skills and a sharp mind.
本物の極道がのう｡
A real yakuza.
ﾃﾒｴは 極道なんかじゃねえ｡
You're no yakuza...
ただの外道だ｡
You're nothing but a scoundrel.
く… ｺｲﾂは…｡
You...
ようやく毒が
効いてきたようじゃのう｡
Seems the poison is finally taking effect.
ｱﾎには
毒も効かんのかと思うたわ｡
I was starting to think poison
doesn't work on a fool.
くぅ…
どうやら酒がまずかったのは➡
I guess the reason the sake tasted bad
男に酌してもらったからだけじゃ
なさそうだな｡
wasn't only because it
was poured by a man.
始末しろ｡
(組員たち)へい！
Finish him.
Right!
Kill him!
(組員たち)やっちまえ！
♪♪～
Come back here!
(組員)待ちやがれ！
♪♪～
うぅ!! う…｡
やってくれるぜ…｡
Now you've done it...
死ねや ｺﾗ!!
Die!
♪♪～
おりゃ～!!
うわっ！
♪♪～
(銃声)
捜せ！ 草の根分けてでも
捜せ～!!
Find him!
Drag the river if you have to, but find him!
Right!
(組員たち)おう！
Brother.
(組員)ｱﾆｷ 今 病院から電話が｡
We just got a call from the hospital.
ｵｼﾞｷが… ｵｼﾞｷが死にました｡
The Boss...
just died.
そうか｡
I see.
やりましたね
これで いよいよ ｱﾆｷの天下！
You did it. Everything is finally yours.
It's the start of the new Mashiroi...no,
the start of the Nakamura Gang.
魔死呂威組 いや
中村組の 立ち上げでさぁ！
引き上げるぞ｡
(組員たち)え？
We're leaving.
Huh?
(中村)ﾃﾒｴら どじょうすくいは
そこまでだ｡
That's enough diving
for sea sludge, guys.
Let's go home. He won't
survive those wounds.
帰るぞ
あの傷じゃ 助かりはせんわ｡
Brother, what about the
kids the Boss called?
ｱﾆｷ ｵｼﾞｷが呼んだ 他のｶﾞｷどもは!?
(中村)ほうっとけ
どうせ 何もできやせん｡
Forget them. They can't
do anything, anyway.
But Brother, if people connected to
the Boss find out, it'll get messy.
(組員)しかし ｱﾆｷ！
おじき派の連中に知れたら➡
ことですぜ！ …ｱﾆｷ!!
(組員たち)ｱﾆｷ!!
Brother!
[The next episode... "Some Things
Are Better Left Unsaid"]
[Gintoki's whereabouts remain unknown.
Shinpachi and Kagura are worried.]
[As Kyojiro attends his inauguration ceremony,
what secret is he hiding?]
[See you next time.]